TARCHANA

Trainer | WordPress Developer | UI Designer

□+91 9969166913 | □ techarchie3@gmail.com | □ Portfolio | □ GitHub | □ LinkedIn | □ Tamilnadu, India

(*SUMMARY OF ONLINE CV)

SUMMARY

I am a creative. My interests brought my hands-on experience in various fields. Some of the major fields are in customer service, technical service, human resource management, trainer and resolution provider, and societal dynamics to further enhance my skills in various dimensions.

EXPERIENCE

PLANET SPARK-REMOTE, International — PUBLIC SPEAKER TRAINER

Feb. 2024 - Present

• International training platform for teaching public speaking & communication skills open to all age group.

MEWALLA CONSULTANCY SERVICE, **Tamilnadu** — WEBSITE DESIGNING March 2024 (Remote)

SARVAM.AI SERVICES PVT. LTD., Karnataka — COUNSELOR (CUSTOMER SUPPORT)

Sep,2023- Nov, 2023 (Remote)

• Counselor for Sarvm Al, Logistics, Retailer & Sales team at SARVM app creators

Lead IAS Junior Academy, **Kerala** — EDUCATIONAL COUNSELLOR

Mar, 2023 - Jul, 2023 (Remote)

• Guide the way to pursue course in the middle of academics for better future.

NGO's, Tamilnadu — SOCIAL SERVICE

2021-2022 (Chennai)

• Teaching on remote, (during COVID) (nonprofit basis, freely)

Mewalla Consultancy Service, **Tamilnadu** — CSR CONSULTANT & CLIENT COORDINATOR

Jul, 2019-Aug, 2020 (Tirunelveli)

(Govt. Initiative handled by Redington foundation for empowerment of youths making them employable especially females including disabled students.)

- Observe problems of villages and conducted village activities for students for their hometown on their requests,
- Client meetings with startups, permit new businesses & developments within firm and thus creating various employability.
- Technical (C, Python, Website development, Frontend, Oracle SQL) and Non Technical training (English communication, Interview skills, Personality development and Public Relationship management).

Vita Institute, **Tamilnadu** — TRAINEE TO BE A TRAINER

2018 (Chennai)

• Guided me of how to train the students for various fields and for competitive exams.

Indeed/UrbanPro/Olx, Tamilnadu — HOMETUTIONS

Mar, 2015 - Dec, 2016 (Chennai)

- home tuitions for a dyslexia student of age 4 for painting.
- Taught for normal students of standards 2nd, 3rd, 4th, 6th, 7th, 9th, 10th

Moon Event Management Services, **Tamilnadu** — EVENT MANAGER

Jun,2014- Jul, 2015 (Chennai)

• Client interaction and negotiating based on the requirements.

EMAAR services, **Tamilnadu** — HR EXECUTIVE

Jan, 2014 - Apr, 2017 (Chennai)

- Servicing & guidelines to get job Jan,2014 Sep,2016, later followed officially in the firms including JS4U where I did selection and screening for interview of freshers and experienced candidates by call.
- Getting tie ups with technical & non technical companies local, MNC's, international companies, Startup's, Finance, BPO & software companies of Chennai, Bangalore, Hyderabad.
- I initiated tie up and got a client of a NEPAL company for solar street lamps project.

SITEL, Tidel Park, Tamilnadu — TECHNICAL SUPPORT EXECUTIVE

Dec 2013 - Feb 2014 (Chennai)

 U.S.A. Customers, troubleshooting hardware & software issues and queries, also handled cold call handling as a customer support executive.

IIHT Institute, **Tamilnadu** — TEMPORARY EDUCATIONAL COUNSELOR

Jul,2013 - Oct,2013 (Chennai)

Counseling students such that they must take the course where they have bright side of the future at IIHT.

ARUN REGA BAKERY & MACHINERIES PVT. LTD., **Tamilnadu** — ELECTRICAL TRAINEE

Dec,2011 - Oct,2012 (Coimbatore)

• Learnt and analysed on PLC SCADA, PCB electrical wiring designing connecting various components and devices to connect for enhancing major machinery functionality behavior such that it is more productive and valuable at output level and less time consuming.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Frontend** HTML5, CSS3, Responsive Web Design, UI design, Framer motion, JavaScript, Wordpress web Development
- Backend Python, Django basics, Oracle SQL, API theory basic knowledge
- Tool Figma, GitHub, ChatGPT, BlackBox.ai, Gemini AI
- Other -, Unity 2d, Unity 3D, Video editing, stickman animation, basic story making and basic animated video making, hacking basic level with coding.
- **Currently learning** Full stack development, [data science, AI with python, cyber security, Robo automation with CATIA & ANSYS and Game development (on hold for completing full stack development rest to be contd. After completion)

PROFESSIONAL PROJECT

- Food delivery app with UI designing
- Ecommerce frontend developed
- Simple Django dashboard with user login id and Password
- Simple coding with the link to hack the device to inverting and rotating the screen of the device
- Complete WordPress Ecommerce Developed.

PROFESSIONAL COURSE

Pantech Solutions collaborated with Warrior AI, Online [first priority]—

Certification in FSD.

November 2024 - Present

Various other online courses yet to be completed—

Certification in Data Science, Cyber Security, Robotic. AI, Game development, Animation.

After completion of FSD to be continued.

SOFT SKILLS

- Effective communication
- Team collaboration
- Problem-solving
- Strong interest in learning and developing new things

EDUCATION

Francis Xavier Engineering College, Anna University, Tirunelveli —

BE (Electronics & Comm. Engg.)

June 2007 - August 2011

National Institute Of Electronics & Information Technology, MoE&IT, Chennai —

PG Diploma (Embedded & VLSI Systems Design)

June 2007 - August 2011

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Tamil
- Malayalam
- & few more languages understandable and speak at basic level